talentlyft.com 2019-06-06

# Privacy policy | TalentLyft Help Center

This Privacy Policy is an integral part of the General Terms of Use of the Website [www.talentlyft.com](https://www.talentlyft.com/en). By accepting the General Terms, User confirms that he is familiar with and agrees with this Privacy Policy. Privacy Policy regulates the collection, storage and use of personal data of Users of the Website and Visitors. 

The protection of Users personal data is one of TalentLyft's priorities and any processing of personal data is carried out conscientiously, legally, in good faith and in accordance with all relevant legislation.

Personal data is every information related an identified person or a person that can be identified, whether his identity can be determined directly or indirectly, in particular on the basis of an identification number or one or more factors specific to his physical, psychological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity.

The processing of personal data entails any action or set of actions performed upon personal data, such as collecting, recording, organising, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, publishing or otherwise making available, alignment, combining, blocking, deletion or destruction and the implementation of logical, mathematical or other operations on that data.

TalentLyft is committed to data protection of our website Visitors and Users. However, we do gather some personal information* to improve our website, to better understand our visitors and their behaviour. This is done via cookies. Please review our Cookie Policy.

In order to become a Website user you have to register. Our Website has a subscription model, therefore we need your private personal information**, including credit card details in order to process charges. TalentLyft does not store Credit Card data. All credit card information is stored on Braintree which is is a validated [Level 1 PCI DSS Compliant Service Provider](https://articles.braintreepayments.com/reference/security/pci-compliance). TalentLyft is not subject to PCI obligations. 

**User  
** By entering personal data during and after the registration on the Website, the User expresses his agreement to the processing of his personal data for the stated purpose based on General Terms.

The User has the right to terminate the agreement at any time and request the termination of further processing of his personal data, except when it comes to processing data for statistical purposes when the aforementioned data does not allow the identification of the person to which they relate.

The User is responsible for the accuracy of the entered information.

**Visitor**  
With access to the Website, the use of content and services which the Website provides and with the submission of information, it is considered that the Visitor consents to the collection, storage and use of personal data in accordance with the conditions specified in this Privacy Policy.  

In case you have any concerns about privacy or your personal information please send us an email to [privacy@talentlyft.com](mailto:privacy@talentlyft.com) with subject line "website privacy concern" and we will reply as soon as possible.

**User**  
TalentLyft collects User data during the registration.

**Visitor**

Visitor data is collected when using the Website and browsing it's content

TalentLyft will not collect and process personal data whose collection is prohibited by law, such as data relating to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or other beliefs, trade union memberships and other data the collection of which the law expressly prohibits, except under the law enumerated conditions and situations.

**User data being collected:**

  * Full name (first name, last name, middle name, title)
  * Headline (job title)
  * Skype name
  * Profile image
  * Phone number
  * Email address
  * Company name
  * Company address

**Visitor data being collected:**

  * IP address
  * Location data

In case when Visitor downloads marketing materials (E-books, resources, tutorials, guides), additional data is collected and stored:

  * First name
  * Last name
  * Job title
  * Email address
  * Phone number

**User**

TalentLyft collects User information for the sole purpose of carrying out activities which are subject of their business. The collected data can be used for further development and improvement of the Website, to adapt and improve the content and services that the Website provides, as well as to inform and offer the User other contents and services that can be used through the Website.

The data that Candidates have entered during registration and while creating and editing their profile on the Website shall only be accessible to other registered Users, who gained access to this data by registering on the Website and have required permissions to access the data.  
Candidate data will be used only by registered Users, and only for purposes of finding appropriate employees.

The data of Users who advertise the need for employment, which refers to the job description and requirements that must be met by potential employees, as well as information that such a User submits while presenting its business activities and their contact information shall be available to all Users and Visitors of the Website.

If you are a User, TalentLyft will use your information to provide you with information and updates about The Website for marketing purposes.

**Visitor  
** TalentLyft collects Visitor data for purposes of optimising Website performance and availability. Additionally, data entered by Visitors themselves, when downloading marketing materials, is used for providing information and updates on relevant content.

TalentLyft will not transmit any personal data to third parties, except in the manner specified in the Policy. Any transfer to third parties must comply with the regulations of the Policy and third parties are bound to comply with the regulations of the Policy regarding data handling. 

User personal data may be transferred to affiliates, third parties that are contracted by TalentLyft to carry out certain activities or provide certain services and in the case of ownership, organisational and status changes regarding TalentLyft, as well as when such an obligation is expressly stipulated by law. In particular, we provide a limited amount of your information (such as your email and address) to Braintree Payment Solutions, LLC when processing credit card payments; Intercom, Inc. (Full name, email and company name) to bring you personalised support experience and Mailgun Technologies Inc. (full name and email address) to send emails.

TalentLyft approaches the storing of personal data conscientiously and with all due care, taking the utmost effort that the data are adequately protected from any form of accidental or deliberate abuse, destruction, loss, unauthorised alteration, disclosure or access.

Personal data transmission takes place via the internet and is, in spite of all efforts, never truly secure, therefore TalentLyft does not guarantee the safety of such a transfer and the User/Visitor performs it at their own risk. After receiving the information from the User/Visitor, TalentLyft will take all necessary measures in order to prevent any misuse of the data.

Personal data can be transferred and stored outside of the Republic of Croatia in countries that provide adequate protection of personal data, as well as in countries located outside of the European Union in which the protection of personal data is possibly not regulated in accordance with the relevant EU legislation and does not provide the adequate level of protection in accordance to relevant EU legislation. By submitting their personal information the User/Visitor agrees to the previously described transmission, storage and use of data.

As stated in article 5. some of the data is being provided to Braintree Payment Solutions, LLC(Braintree), Intercom, Inc.(Intercom), Mailgun Technologies Inc.(Mailgun) companies based outside of EU. TalentLyft provides its customers with highest level of data security and compliance, and in accordance to that conducts business only with companies that can provide the same level of security. [Braintree](https://www.braintreepayments.com/en-hr/legal/payment-services-agreement-eu), [Intercom](https://www.intercom.com/security) and [Mailgun](https://www.mailgun.com/gdpr) provide EU General Data Protection Regulation ([GDPR](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/data-protection-reform/overview-of-the-gdpr/)) compliance.

Customers data is stored in multi-tenant data-stores, we do not have individual data-stores for each customer. However strict privacy controls exist in our application code to ensure data privacy and prevent one customer from accessing another customers data. We have many unit and integration tests in place to ensure these privacy controls work as expected. These tests are run every time our code base is updated and even one single test failing will prevent new code being shipped to production.

All data sent to or from TalentLyft is encrypted in transit using 256 bit encryption. TalentLyft is served 100% over HTTPS. 

TalentLyft will notify the User/Visitor whether or not his personal data is being collected on the basis of a written request by the User/Visitor and in accordance with the General Terms, the Privacy Policy and applicable regulations and will enable the User/Visitor to correct or delete entered information. The User/Visitor that wishes to exercise the aforementioned right, may contact TalentLyft by sending an email to the address [privacy@talentlyft.com](mailto:privacy@talentlyft.com).

Your personal information will be retained until it is deleted. Your personal information will be deleted on one of the following occurrences:

  * deletion of your personal information by you, the User(or by another person engaged by the User, where you are using the Website and/or Services on behalf of a User).
  * where you are a Candidate, deletion of your personal information by an User(Company) on whose behalf we are processing your personal information.
  * written request by you to us ([privacy@talentlyft.com](mailto:privacy@talentlyft.com))
  * automatically, after 1 year of inactivity upon active subscription expiration or cancellation

If you are a Candidate, any request by you to us to delete your personal information will not result in deletion of any application submitted by you to a User(Company)(in respect of which we are a data processor and not a data controller). If you require a Company to delete an application, or any other information provided by you to the Company directly, you must contact the Company to request such deletion.

As stated in the article 13. of the General Terms – all of your data belongs to you. At any time, you can request your data to be exported in whole, and handed over to you in a machine-readable format (JSON). 

The data shall be available for export until it’s deleted in accordance with the article 9. of this Privacy Policy.

Data export shall be done free of charge.

We have a dedicated Data Protection Officer to help you with any requests or questions you have about your data. You can reach out to us by emailing [privacy@talentlyft.com](mailto:privacy@talentlyft.com).

TalentLyft has the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. Any alteration of this Privacy Policy will be published on this Website and any User that wishes to use the contents and services provided by this Website, will be obliged to accept any modification of the Policy.

\----------------------

_*Data collected this way is your internet service provider name, the page from which you visited our site, your behavior on our website (which sections of the Website you accessed, date, time and duration of your visit)._

_**Personal information needed for subscription to the Website: your name, address, email address, telephone number and credit card details._

\----------------------

Effective: January 14th, 2019
